Federico Benavidez

IT OPERATIONS MANAGER | ITIL 4 CERTIFIED | INCIDENT MANAGER

Details

Buenos Aires Argentina +54 9 11 3249-1172 fedebenavidez@live.com

Links

LinkedIn

Areas of Expertise

Cloud Computing

Incident Management

Networking

Languages

Spanish

English

Portuguese

Hobbies

Videogames industry, mind-blowing Movies & TV Shows, Esports, drones (FPV), programming.

About

I'm a IT professional from Argentina who counts with more than 10 years of experience working for global companies, supporting and managing vast, diverse and complex infrastructures.

I consider myself a DevOps enthusiast, tech-savvy and geek by nature. I'm very passionate about learning new things. Currently studying Portuguese through an in-company training institute, learning JavaScript to add to my knowledge in C and Python, and planning on completing a DevSecOps certification by Hackademy starting in March '23.

Last but not least, I have reached EFSET's C2 proficiency in English.

Experience

IT Operations Manager, Wellness Services / Fully

JULY 2022 - PRESENT

Start-up company with presence in AR & BR where I'm accountable for IT Operations. Currently planning the IT Ops Support model for when the company decouples from the parent firm (Prudential International). Tech & management tools: Agile methodologies, AWS, Jenkins, Terraform.

- Negotiated contracts with vendors.
- Support the business by leading IT initiatives among internal and 3rd party teams.
- Direct manager for +5 tech collaborators.
- · Responsible for IT inventory and vulnerability management.

IT Infrastructure Operations Manager, PwC Argentina

NOVEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2022

Accountable for Latin America Operations, where we had to perform hardware refresh, upgrades, vulnerability management and cloud migrations; all of that while promoting alignment to the PwC's Global strategy.

- Manage relationship with Americas IT and global vendors.
- Support Change Management processes (CAB, PIR, approvals) for the region.
- Manage Major Incidents (including Problem Management) and escalations.
- IT budget, SLA & KPI reviews.

Outage Specialist (Supervising Associate), EY

JULY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2020

Drove the restoration and recovery activities for high priority and severity incidents as a member of the Global Outage Management Center. Declared high priority incidents in accordance with industry standards of ITIL for major incident management within the IT infrastructure.

- Coordinated global teams on time critical and complex remediation activities to restore impacted infrastructure services to business-as-usual.
- Coaching of new staff, providing guidance for their activities and constructive feedback.

Network Support Level 3 (Senior Associate), EY

NOVEMBER 2014 - JULY 2016

Level 3 escalations for network related incidents. Gained knowledge in DNS, extended wireless networks, DHCP, load balancers and data center architectures (Cisco Nexus).

• Infrastructure maintenance and configuration tasks (both planned and emergency).

• Problem analysis and troubleshoot regarding load balancing, DNS, routing & switching.

Infrastructure Support Level 2 (Senior Associate), EY

JANUARY 2014 - NOVEMBER 2014

Infrastructure Support for network, voice and security related incidents.

- 24/7 Follow-the-sun model, providing global support in a multicultural team.
- Coordination with local support teams when remote-hands were necessary.
- Consolidated experienced in EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, first-hop redundancy protocols, Layer 2 loops mitigation techniques, packet sniffing, DNS, extended wireless networks, DHCP, load balancers and data center architectures.

NOC Operator, Industrial And Commercial Bank of China

SEPTEMBER 2013 - DECEMBER 2013

Management and support to the enterprise network. Gained experience in the following network protocols: STP, VTP, HSRP, InterVLAN routing, L3 multilayer switching, GRE/IPSec tunneling, EIGRP and OSPF.

• Administration of Cisco routers and switches, Juniper firewalls, Riverbed's WAN Optimization Controllers,

load-balancing technologies (F5), Cisco UCM for VoIP, and Nagios monitoring tools

 Diagnose and failure detection, proactive monitoring of services, branches and critical links.

NOC Operator, Claro Argentina

JANUARY 2012 - JULY 2013

Network administrator for Telmex external Customers located in US & LATAM; gained experience in multiple network protocols and technologies: BGP over MPLS, iBGP, OSPF, VPN.

- WAN Services management (MPLS, Internet VPN, Point-to-Point)
- Troubleshooting and recovery plans for Service disruptions.
- Vendor management and escalations.
- Single point of contact for major clients.
- Collaborated with the Designing and Implementation teams.

Education

Bachellor's in IT & Business Management, Universidad de Palermo

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

Courses

[Certified] ITIL® 4 Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

[Certified] CCNA® (Cisco Certified Network Associate)

DECEMBER 2011 - DECEMBER 2014

Architecting on AWS — Solutions Arch., IT College

SEPTEMBER 2021

MS-AZ 103 Azure Administrator, IT College

JULY 2019